Finding Aid for Middle English Dictionary records, 1925-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Non- MED MATERIALS
  - Manuscript Concordances and Collections by Charles Crawford
    - Avisa Series I
      - Volume II (pp. 476-935) (Box 88)
        Sir John Davies: Hymns of Astraea in Acrostic Verse (1599): pp. 935a-935N (copied from Edward Arber's An English Garner, vol. 5)
      - Volume III (pp. 936-1365) (Box 88)
        (Brief extracts from various authors and works, scattered throughout the volume on the following pages:)
        Nicholas Breton: (pp. 936-41, 984-99: Extracts from Daffodils and Primroses (1593); pp. 998-1003 Five pieces from the Tanner MS of Breton's works; pp. 958-81: Extracts from The Toyes of an Idle Head (1582); pp. 982-83: Extract from The Strange Fortunes of Two Excellent Princes (1600); pp. 1022-25: Extracts from The Wil of Wit (?1582); pp. 1316-21, 1334-37: Extracts from Melancholike Humours (1600) (copied from A.B. Grosart's edition of Breton [1879]); 1338-41: Extracts from An Olde Man's Lesson and a Young Man's Love (1605))
        Richard Edwards: (pp. 942-45, 1040-43: Extracts from The Paradyse of Dainty Devises (1576))
        William Byrd: (pp. 946-57: Extracts from First Book of Psalms, Sonnets, andSongs of Sadness and Piety (1588))
        John Taylor:: (pp. 1004-5: Extract from The Sculler (1612)
        George Whetstone: (pp. 1006-7: Extract from The Rock of Regard (1576); pp. 1026-29: Extract from An Heptameron (1582); pp. 1034-35: Extract from The English Myrror (1586)
        George Gascoigne: (pp. 1008-9: Extract from The Steele Glasse (1576); pp. 1012-17: Extracts from The Posies (1575 edition))
        Edmund Spenser: (pp. 1010-11: Extract from The Faerie Queene (1590))
        Timothy Kendall: pp. 1018-19, 1084-93:Extracts from Flowers of Epigrammes (1577)
        Roger Cotton: (pp. 1020-21: Extract from A Spirituall Song containing an Historicall Discourse (1596))
        William Browne: (pp. 1030-33: Extract from Britannia's Pastorals (?1625))
        Robert Toft: (pp. 1036-39: Extracts from Laura (1597) (copied from Arber's An English Garner, 8.27, 340)
        Richard Barnfield: (pp. 1044-67B: Extracts from Greenes Funeralls (1594) (copied from R.B. McKerrow's edition of 1911))
        [John Bodenham]: (pp. 1067E-F, 1078-83: Extracts from Politenphinia, Wits Commonwealth (1650 and 1597 editions respectively); pp. 1068-75: Extracts from England's Helicon (1600); pp. 1076-77, 1094-1109 Extracts from Belvedere, or The Garden of the Muses (1600)
        [John Lyly]: (pp. 1109A-D: "Of lingering Love," a poem from Rawlinson MS. Poet. 148, ff. 2-3 (copied from Bond's edition, III.463))
        Clement Robinson et alii: pp. 1109F-J: "A Warning for Lovers" from A Handefull of Pleasant Delites (1584) (copied from Heliconia edition, p. 53)
        The Phoenix Nest (1593): (pp. 1110-1251 Extracts (copied from Heliconia edition, pp. 28-147 passim); pp. 1252B-77: "A Most Rare and Excellent Dreame" (copied from A.H. Bullen's Shorter Elizabethan Poems [1903], p. 129); (1600) (from Bullen, p. 107))
        John Wilbye: (pp. 1280-81: "[Woe-begone me]", from The First Set of English Madrigals (1598) (copied from Bullen's Shorter Elizabethan Poems, p. 151))
        Sir Philip Sidney: (pp. 1282B-87: Extracts from the Arcadia (1593) (copied from Grosart's edition, 3.218); pp. 1286-87: Extract from the Arcadi a (1590); pp. 1342-45: Dedication to Astrophel and Stella (1591) (copied from Grosart's edition, 3.212))
        Christopher Marlowe: (pp. 1288B-91: Epistle by Thomas Thorpe prefixed to Marlowe's translation of The First Booke of Lucan (1600) (copied from Dyce's edition [1858], p. 369); pp. 1292-93: Dedication by Edward Blunt to Hero and Leander (1598) (from Dyce, p. 277); pp. 1294-97: "Ignoto Verses in Marlowe's Works" (from Dyce, p. 366)
        Thomas Proctor et al. The Gorgeous Gallery of Gallant Inventions (1578): (pp. 1298B-99: "Verses by A.M." (copied from Heliconia edition, p. ix); pp. 1300-1307 Verses by Owen Roydon (copied from Heliconia edition, pp. x, 1)
        Robert Allott: (pp. 1308-11: Dedication and "To the Reader" from England's Parnassus (1600) (copied from Crawford's edition [1913], pp. 3, 4))
        Richard Al[l]ison: (Extract from An Howres Recreation in Musicke (1606) (copied from Bullen's Shorter Elizabethan Poems, p. 264))
        Author Uncertain: (pp. 1322-25: "A Farewell to the Vanities of the World" (copied from John Hannah Works of Wotton and Raleigh [1910], p. 109))
        Robert Southwell: (pp. 1345C-49: Dedication by H.W. to A Foure-fold Meditation of the Foure Last Things (1606))
        Francis Davison et alii: (pp. 1350-55: "The Lie," a poem from A Poetical Rhapsody (1602) (copied from Bullen's edition, 1.28))
        Anthony Munday: pp. 1356-65: Introductory matter to A Banquet of Daintie Conceits (1588) (copied from Park's edition of the anthology printed in The Harleian Miscellany [1812], 9.219)
        Alexander Niccholes: (pp. 1365A-Z: Extracts from A Discourse of Marriage and Wiving (1615) (copied from The Harleian Miscellany [1744-46], 2.141-67))
      - Volume IV (pp. 1366-1895) (Box 88)
        John Dowland: (pp. 1366-67: "[Too chaste, and too cruel]," extract from The Third and Last Booke of Songs or Aires (1603) (copied from Bullen's Shorter Elizabethan Poems, p. 119))
        Thomas Deloney: (pp. 1368-71: Dedication to Jack of Newberie (?1597) (copied from F.O. Mann's edition [1912], p. 2); pp. 1374-79: Dedications (2) to The Gentle Craft, Part II (?1597); pp. 1420-23: Dedication to "Canaan's Calamatie," from The Works (1597), vol. 2)
        Sir Edward Dyer (alleged): pp. 1380-93: Two poems ("[The Man of Woe]" and "A Fancy") (copied from Hannah's Poems of Wotton and Raleigh [1910], pp. 153 and 154); pp. 1882-87: "My Mind to me a Kingdom is" (copied from Percy's Reliques (with collations from the Rawlinson manuscript and from Byrd's First Book of Psalms, Sonnets, and Songs [1588])
        Sir Philip Sidney: pp. 1580-1627 Poems appended to the Arcadia (1598) (copied from Arber's English Garner, II.171-93); pp. 1628-43: Additions to Astrophel and Stella first found in the Arcadia (1598) (copied from Grosart,Complete Poems, I.54, 185, et passim and Arber's English Garner, I.521, 573, et passim); pp. 1644-59: Poems (not by Sidney) added to Newman's "surreptitious" edition of Astrophel and Stella (1591) (copied from Arber's English Garner, I.582-600 passim); pp. 1672-73: Henry Olney's address to the reader from his edition of An Apologie for Poetrie (1595); pp. 1674-89: Extracts from Book VI of the Arcadia (1624) attributed toRichard Beling (copied from the Routledge edition of the Arcadia... with the additions of... Richard Beling [1907 or 1921], pp. 630-78 passim.
        Arthur Bourch(i)er:: (pp. 1660-67: Poems printed in Geffrey Whitney A Choice of Emblemes (1586), and The Paradyse of Dainty Devises (1576))
        William Byrd: (pp. 1690-1709 1756-63: Extracts from Psalms, Sonnets, and Songs of Sadness and Piety (1588) (copied from Bullen's Shorter Elizabethan Poems, pp. 3-21 passim); pp. 1710-41: Extracts from Songs of Sundrie Natures (1589) (copied from Bullen, pp. 27-49 passim); pp. 1742-55: Extracts from the 2nd Book of Songs and Sonnets (1611) (copied from Bullen, pp. 52-58); pp. 1848-49: La Verginella" (copied from Bullen, p. 75))
        George Whetstone: (pp. 1764-67: Publisher's Dedication (by Thomas Cadman) to his edition of the Elegy on Sir Philip Sidney (?1586 or 1587))
        John Wilbye: (pp. 1854-55, 1859-61: Extracts from the 1st Set of Madrigals (1598) (copied from Bullen,Shorter Elizabethan Poems, pp. 152 and 145, 147))
        Edward de Vere, Earl of Oxford: (pp. 1856-57: "Fain would I sing, etc." from Poems (a1604) (copied from John Hannah's Poems of Sir Walter Raleigh... with those of Sir Henry Wotton and other courtly poets [1910]))
        Christopher Marlowe: pp. 1878-79: R[ichard] J[ones]'s address to the readers from Tamburlaine (1590)
        Sir Walter Raleigh: (pp. 1880-81: "Fain would I, but I dare not," verses found in MS. Rawlinson 41, f. 41 (copied from Hannah's Poems of Sir Walter Raleigh... with those of Sir Henry Wotton [1910]))
        John Lyly (?): (pp. 1888-95: Six poems found in MS. Additional 22,601 (copied from Bond's edition, III.451-53))
    - Avisa Series II
      (As in Series I, unless noted, the texts are on the odd-numbered pages (with short notes in the righthand margins), often preceded by introductory matter on both odd-and even-numbered pages; longer notes are on the even-numbered pages; and some pages are blank, primarily even-numbered ones, as well as occasional odd-numbered ones at the ends of texts.)
      - Volume I (pp. 1-501N) (Box 88)
        (Brief extracts from various authors and works, scattered throughout the volume on the following pages:
        Nicholas Breton: (pp. 1-41: The Countess of Pembroke's Passion (n.d.; 1st published in 1853 by J.O. Halliwell, A Brief Description of the Ancient and Modern Manuscripts Preserved in the Public Library, Plymouth... [privately printed]);pp. 42-93: The Countess of Pembroke's Love (1592 printed with the following item); pp. 94-197: The Pilgrimage to Paradise (1592))
        Thomas Watson:: (pp. 198-255: The Tears of Fancy (1593) Bartholomew Griffin: pp. 256-327: Fidessa, more chaste then kind (1596)?)
        John Chalkhill: (pp. 327A-403: Alcilia: Philoparthen's Loving Folly (1595) (copied from A.H. Bullen, An English Garner [1903]))
        Francis Davison et alii: (pp. 403A-501: Selections from A Poetical Rapsodie (1602) (copied from Bullen's edition [1890-91], volumes I and II passim))
        William Shakespeare: (pp. 501A-501J: Dedication and address to readers from the "First Folio" of Shakespeare's works (1623) (copied from The Shakespeare Allusion-Book, I.313-16); pp. 501K-501N: Title page and address to the reader from The Tragedy of Othello (1622))
      - Volume II (pp. 502-1005) (Box 88)
        Francis Davison et alii: pp. 502-97: Extracts from A Poetica Rapsodie (1602) (copied from Bullen's edition, vol. II passim); pp. 892-917: Poems by various authors from A Poetical Rapsodie (1602) (copied from Bullen's edition, vol. II passim and I.86)
        R. B.: pp. 598-647B: Orpheus his Journey to Hell (1595)
        [J. Bodenham]: pp. 648-773: Extracts from England's Helicon (1600) (copied from Bullen's edition passim)
        Richard Barnfield: (pp. 776-91, 829a-29b: The Affectionate Shepheard (1594), Part I (this and the following are all copied from E. Arber's edition [1882]); pp. 792-813: The Affectionate Shepheard (1594), Part II; pp. 814-29:The Shepherds Content, from The Affectionate Shepheard (1594); pp. 830-35:The Complaint of Chastitie, from The Affectionate Shepheard (1594); pp. 836-43:Hellens Rape, from The Affectionate Shepheard (1594); pp. 848-59: Cynthia, with certain Sonnets and the Legend of Cassandra (1595); pp. 860-85:Cassandra, from Cynthia (1595); pp. 886-91: Extracts from Poems in Diverse Humors (1598)
        William Shakespeare:(pp. 919-29, 935 (lower half): Sonnets (1609)
        Henry Chettle::pp. 930-35 (upper half): Address "To the Gentlemen Readers" from Kind-Hartes Dreame (1592) (copied from the Bodley Head reprint [1923]); pp. 944-65: Extracts from England's Mourning Garment (1603) (copied from The Harleian Miscellany, ed. W. Oldys [1744-46]) ?J[ohn] H[ind]: pp. 936-43: Extracts from The Mirrour of Worldly Fame (1603) (copied from The Harleian Miscellany, ed. W. Oldys [1744-46])
        Richard Niccols: (pp. 966-77, 997-99: Epicedium (1603) (copied from Bond's edition [1902], I.509-16)?
        John Lyly: 978-81: "Entertainment to Elizabeth at Cowdray" (1591); pp. 983-85: "Entertainment to Elizabeth at Elvetham" (1591); pp. 985-89: "Entertainment to Elizabeth at Quarrendon" (1592); p. 991: "Entertainment to Elizabeth at Sudeley" (1592) (all copied from Bond's edition, vol. I passim)
        Robert Southwell: (pp. 992-93: Dedication by the publisher, W. Barret, from a 1620 collection of Southwell's Poems (copied from W.B. Turnbull, The Poetical Works [1856]); pp. 994-95: Verses by the publisher from Southwell's Triumphs over Death (1595)
      - Volume III (pp. 1006-1407) (Box 88)
        Robert Jones (pp. 1013-21, 1024-27: Extracts from The First Booke of Songes and Ayres (1600) (copied from Bond's edition of Lyly, vol. III passim); pp. 1022-23: Extract from Muses Gardin for Delights (1610) (copied from Bond, III.490))
        Nicholas Breton:
        pp. 1028-97: Melancholike Humours (1600) (copied from G.B. Harrison's edition [1929])
        pp. 1112-19: Extracts from The Wil of Wit (1599) (copied from Elizabethan and Jacobean Pamphlets, pp. 112, 85-86)
        pp. 1137-97: The Passionate Shepheard (1604) (copied from Grosart's edition)
        pp. 1198-1201 Extract from Pasquils Mad-cappe (1626)
        pp. 1202-1209 Extracts from Pasquils Fooles-cap (1600)
        pp. 1211-17: Extracts from Pasquils Passe and passeth not (1600)
        pp. 1218-19: Title page to A Solemne Passion of the Soules Love (1623)
        pp. 1220-25: Extracts from The Ravisht Soule and the Blessed Weeper (1601)
        pp. 1226-33: Extracts from The Longing of a Blessed Heart (1601)
        pp. 1234-37: Extracts from The Soules Harmony (1602)
        pp. 1238-43: Extracts from The Mothers Blessing (1602)
        pp. 1244-51: Extracts from The Soules Immortall Crowne (1605)
        pp. 1252-55: Extracts from A True Description of Unthankfulnesse (1602)
        pp. 1256-59: Extracts from The Honour ofValour (1605)
        pp. 1260-61: Extract from An Invective against Treason (1616)
        pp. 1262-65: Extracts from I Would and I Would not (1614)
        pp. 1266-67: Title page to The Workes of a young Wit (1577)
        pp. 1268-69: Poem attributed to Breton from John Hind's Eliosto Libidinoso (1606)
        pp. 1270-75: Extracts from Auspicante Jehova (1597)
        pp. 1276-79: Extracts from Wits Trenchmour (1597)
        pp. 1280-87: Extracts from A Floorish upon Fancie (1582)
        pp. 1288-89: Extracts from The Scholler and the Souldiour (1599)
        pp. 1290-93: Extracts from The Miseries of Mavillia (1599)
        pp. 1294-99: Extracts from The Praise of Vertuous Ladies (1599)
        pp. 1300-1305 Extracts from The Strange Fortunes of Two Excellent Princes (1600)
        pp. 1306-1309 Title pages to Crossing of Proverbs (n.d./1616);)
        pp. 1013-21, 1024-27: Extracts from The First Booke of Songes and Ayres (1600) (copied from Bond's edition of Lyly, vol. III passim)
        pp. 1022-23: Extract from Muses Gardin for Delights (1610) (copied from Bond, III.490))
        pp. 1256-59: Extracts from The Honour of Valour (1605)
        Sir Philip Sidney: (pp. 1098-99: Poem from "Pansies" (?copied from A.B. Grosart The Complete Poems [1877]))
        Ralph Sidley: (pp. 1100-1103 "Verses of Praise" (in Robert Greene Greenes Never Too Late [1590], Parts I and II) (copied from Grosart's edition of Greene's Part I Never Too Late and Francesco's Fortunes, or Part II Never Too Late))
        Richard Stapleton: (pp. 1104-1105 "To the Author," verses prefixed to George Chapman's Ovid's Banquet of Sense (1595) (copied from the Chatto & Windus edition, p. l iii); pp. 1128-31: "To the Curteous and Courtly Ladies of England," verses praising Robert Greene's Mamillia, Part II (1593) (copied from Grosart's Works of Robert Greene [1881-86], II.146-48))
        R.S.: (pp. 1106-1107 (upper part): "In prayse of Gascoignes 'Posies',"verses from George Gascoigne's The Posies (1575) (copied from J.W. Cunliffe's edition of The Complete Works [1907-10], 1.20); pp. 1106-1107 (lower part): verses commending Spenser's The Faerie Queene I)
        [D.]: (pp. 1108-1109 "In prayse of Gascoigne and his 'Posies'," verses from George Gascoigne's The Posies (1575))
        [George Gascoigne]: (pp. 1110-1111 "The Printer in commendation of Gascoigne and his works," verses from George Gascoigne's The Posies (1575))
        Sir Henry Wotton: (pp. 1120-27: Extracts from Reliquiae Wottonianae (1651-85) (copied from John Hannah's Poems of Sir Walter Raleigh... with those of Sir Henry Wotton and other courtly poets [1875 or 1910]))
        G.B.: (p. 1133 "In Praise of the Author and his Booke," verses praising Robert Greene's Mamillia, Part II (1593) (copied from A.B. Grosart's Works of Robert Greene [1881-86], 2.249-50))
        Ed. Percy(: p. 1135 Verses "In Praise of the Author" of Greene's)
        Alcida (1617): (copied from A.B. Grosart's Works of Robert Greene (1881-86), 9.9-10)
        Samuel Pick: (pp. 1400-1401 Printed note on his Festum Voluptatis, Or the Banquet of Pleasure (1639))
    - Belvedere Concordance
      ([Charles Crawford], "Belvedere, or The Garden of the Muses. 1600." In Crawford's hand, compiled by him after 31 October 1929 (see date on Vol. I, p. 71). Occasional pages are blank.)
      - Volume I (pp. 1-540) (Box 89)
        pp. 1-2: "Index" to Volume I and a few notes about the Spenser Society edition (1875) of Belvedere, from which the quotations are copied
        p. 3: Original title page, with Belvedere spelled Bel-vedere
        p. 4: Note by Crawford explaining that the following list was drawn up by him and differs from the original and that for convenience he has arranged the extracts by numbers from 1 to 4482
        pp. 5-7: "An Alphabetical List of the Sections" (by subject, from "Advice" to "Zeal")
        p. 9: "October 31, 1929. Index of Quotations Identified."
        pp. 9-69 (odd pages): "Index" proper, alphabetically arranged by author or work; pp. 8-68 (even pages): notes passim on various items in the Index
        p. 71: "Other Quotations Identified after October 31, 1929" (4 items)
        p. 78: Note by Crawford that the address on the next page was written by Nicholas Breton
        pp. 79-89 (odd pages): "To the Reader," with occasional notes in the right margins
        pp. 89-93 (odd pages): "The Conclusion" (to the address)
        pp. 95-101 (odd pages): Sonnets and "Verses of Commendation"
        p. 102: Notes by Crawford on what follows
        pp. 103-540: Quotations numbered 1-1467
      - Volume II (pp. 541-1060) (Box 89)
        pp. 541-1060 Quotations numbered 1468-3949
      - Volume III (pp. 1061-1310) (Box 89)
        pp. 1171-1227 (odd pages): "Title-pages etc." (155 items, arranged alphabetically by author)
        pp. 1229-1310 "Index to Notes" (alphabetically arranged by author or work)
    - A Breton Concordance. After 1928
      (see Avisa Series I); Volume 8 has the date "10 December 1932" in pencil on the back of the front cover, but it is not in Crawford's hand. Each page is divided into five columns headed: "Series" [either I or II], "Page" [within each series], "Line" [on the page], [Quotation], and "Author)
      - Volume 1 (pp. 1-508): a -- brand (Box 89)
      - Volume 2 (pp. 1-542): brass -- dedicatory (Box 89)
      - Volume 3 (pp. 1-547): deed --fatal (Box 89)
      - Volume 4 (pp. 1-541): fate -- greyhound (Box 89)
      - Volume 5 (pp. 1-546): grief -- labour (Box 90)
      - Volume 6 (pp. 1-545): labored -- measure (Box 90)
      - Volume 7 (pp. 1-540): measured -- plain (Box 90)
      - Volume 8 (pp. 1-539): plained -- secrecy (Box 90)
      - Volume 9 (pp. 1-545): secret -- subque (Box 90)
      - Volume 10 (pp. 1-541): subscribe -- vow (Box 90)
      - Volume 11 (pp. 1-388): vowed -- z (Box 90)
    - Other Volumes
      - Charles Crawford, "A Concordance to the 1616 Folio edition of Ben Jonson's Works, and the first edition of Every Man in his Humour. "circa 1914 (Box 91)
        (Compiled some time after "1914" (a date Crawford refers to in his introduction) occasional pages are blank)
        pp. I-III: Title (on p. I) and introduction to the "Concordance" (pp. I-III)
        pp. 1-576: Word Index
        p. 576 (lower down): "Plan of the Concordance"
        pp. 577-96: "Verbatim extract from the Concordance," from Winchester to Wisp
        pp. 597-658: "Key to the Numbering of the lines in the 1616 Folio": (a comparative chart of the line-numbering of the 1616 folio, Cunningham's edition of William Gifford's edition of 1816 and Edward Moxon's edition of 1838 (and its reissue of 1858)
      - [Charles Crawford], Concordance to "John Lyly's Euphues (Arber)." (Box 91)
        (No date in volume, but after 1868 the date of Edward Arber's edition of Euphues, or, more likely, the later reprint of it in 1895. The Concordance proper (Part A) appears not to be in Crawford's hand, but Part B is.)
        A: pp. 1-257: Concordance proper, from Abate to Zulho (but the latter word is crossed out and replaced by a similar word beginning with a foreign [?Egyptian] capital letter), followed by 42 unnumbered pages)
        B: unidentified texts (beginning at the end of the volume, upside down, and continuing back towards the center of the volume, are two items, both in Crawford's hand)
        [England's Parnassus] (7 pages (only 2 through 6 are numbered, with each number circled) with "England's Parnassus" (and "Collier's edition" on p. 1) along the tops of the pages and columns; the columns are headed: "No." (from 1 to 191), "Page" (from 1 to 44), "Subject" (alphabetically arranged), "Author", "References and Date"; ends imperfectly 5 lines into p. [7]; one blank page follows)
        [Belvedere] (40 unnumbered pages beginning "Belvedere," with columns headed: "Belvedere (No. [from 1 to 4482]/Section)", "Wits Commonwealth (No./Section/Signature)", "Wits Treasury (No./Section/Signature)", "Wits Theater (No./Section/Signature)", "Found in Author/Work", and "Englands Parnassus (No.)"; the first 14 pages ("Belvedere" through item 399) have some blanks filled in, but only occasional additions after that)
      - Charles Crawford, Index to "Wits Treasury, 1598" (Box 91)
        ((running title across tops of pages). On an unnumbered page before p. I: "Charles Crawford London. The Index was finished July 10, 1914." pp. I-XXV are blank, followed by another 47 unnumbered blank pages, pp. 1-494: Index proper, from Aaron to Zephyrus)
      - [Charles Crawford], "Lines of Poems by Surrey, Wyatt and authors in Tottel's Miscellany and other places arranged in alphabetical order." (Box 91)
        (No date in volume (but after 1895 the date of Edward Arber's edition of Tottel's Miscellany) 4 unnumbered leaves before p. 1, on the first of which (recto and verso): Title (as above) and notes on the editions used by Crawford in his Concordance: Arber's edition (1895) of Tottel's Miscellany for most of the poems; Robert Bell's editions in The Annotated Edition of the English Poets (1854) for the poems of Wyatt and for those poems of Surrey that are not in the Miscellany; the sources of all other quotations are noted at the appropriate places in the volume. For the "Index of Words" he used the Aldine edition of Surrey and Wyatt (1908), and for other authors Tottel's Miscellany.)
        pp. 1-384: Concordance from A to Zeal
        pp. 385-499: "Index of Words in Surrey, Wyatt, and Tottel's Miscellany ", alphabetically arranged from "A.W." (then "Aback") to "Zoroas"
      - [Charles Crawford], Miscellaneous Volume. Dated by Crawford after 31 October 1914 (see Part B, item 2). (Box 91)
        - Part A (in various hands):
          The History of the two Maids of More-clacke, with the life and simple maner of John in the Hospitall... Written by Robert Armin... London: Printed by N.O. for Thomas Archer... 1609"
          (pp. 1-66: a copy of the play from the original edition (this piece appears not to be in Crawford's hand, but looks more like the hand of the Concordance to Lyly's Euphues above))
          A Concordance to Hamlet, The Quarto of 1603 (Aldis Wright's Reprint) & The Folio Play (modernised by Professor E. Dowden"; only the beginning of the Concordance appears, from "A" to "Believe" (pp. 69-105, in a hand quite different from Crawford's)